ROSTYSLAV SEMANYSHYN

CONTACTS

tetiross@gmail.com tetiross.github.io Ternopil, Ukraine

EDUCATION

Ternopil State 'Ivan Pul'uj' Technical University

Masters Degree in Computer Science

LANGUAGES

English - Advanced Ukrainian - Native

PROFILE

Ruby on Rails developer with 8+ years of commercial experience. Worked on a different kind of projects including: healthcare, social networks, finance, datings, e-commerce etc.

I care about clients business and not just thoughtlessly do tasks but always think about the problem that they should solve and therefore the best ways to implement solution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SoftServe | Sep. 2022 - Present | Remote

Lead Software Engineer

 migrating very old Rails application to the most recent version of Rails and Ruby

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Splunk, AWS, Docker

N-iX (Seeking Alpha) | Jul. 2021 - Sep. 2022 | Remote

Ruby on Rails Backend Developer

• taking part in developing features and updating current architecture to improve main system processes

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, Sphinx

Crunch (Saleship) | Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2021 | Remote

Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer / Project Lead Developer

- maintaining and developing E-Commerce application built on multiple microservices
- managing team
- improving development process
- working with different martkeplaces API
- setting up and managing servers for core application and microservices

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Vue.js, PostgreSQL, Git, Amazon MWS API.

MLSDev | Feb. 2017 - Aug. 2019 | Remote

Ruby on Rails Backend Developer

- developing MVP projects in a variety of spheres (healthcare, e-commerce, dating, social networks, etc.)
- direct communication with clients
- performing code reviews
- developing local template project, and reusable solutions

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, Git, AWS services (S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, MediaConvert).

Hmarynka Studio | Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2016 | Ternopil, Ukraine

Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer

- improving skills by working under a mentorship of experienced developer
- solely developing full stack finance project for US market
- performing local presentations

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Heroku, Git.